# JAMAL-E ROUGUI

### Backend Java Developer



(+33) 6 60 444 936



jamal.rougui@gmail.com



/in/jamal-rougui-45462624/



jerougui/jerougui.github.io

# Profile -

Backend Developer professionally with 11+ years of experience in the software development cycle. Theory and practice in object-oriented modeling, design patterns, and data structures. Self learner, active technology watch, passion for problem-solving, and analysis of the complexity of algorithms in time and space to find efficient algorithmic solutions. Development of web and stand-alone applications using Java and C.

# Technical Skills ——



#### **Programming**

 $\rightarrow 5 high$ 

Java • JavaFx • RxJava • Hibernate

JEE • WS • Front

C++ • Python • Machine Learning

## Education.

#### PhD., Computer Science

University of Nantes 2004 - 2008 | Nantes, France

MSc., Info&Telecom University Mohammed V 2002 - 2004 | Rabat, Maroc

## **Experience**

#### Jun 2015 present

- Lead and back-end Java Dev
- SII for Thales SIX GTS France
- Lead and contribute to the implementation of improvements and PO support.
- Design and develop following the Scrum, squad-team framework.
- Design unit tests, end-to-end test and black-box test using JSON.
- Maintains technical documentation

Java8, RxJava, JavaFx, Spring, Hibernate, H2 database in memory, Liquibase, Devops, EasyMock, Git, Rest, Jenkins.

### Oct 2014 -

#### Full Stack developer

SII - for INSEE, SII-Nantes

Jun 2015

- Write technical requirement specification.
- Front-end migration IE to firefox using javascript and JQuery.
- Build and maintain a web application

JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY, ASP, IIS7, JAVASCRIPT, NSIS, ADMINSTUDIO REPACKAGER, INSTALLSHEILD, SVN.

#### Apr 2013 -Jun 2015

#### **Developer Java/Swing**

SII - for HMX-HYPERVISION

- Design and develop a stand-alone application based SWING IHM
- Assist end users to ensure continuity of service

JAVA, SWING, ANT, PROCESSING, VLC-J, XSTREAM, J2DXX, LAUNCH4J, INNO SETUP

#### May 2014 -Sep 2014

### JEE developer

SII - for NEXTER

- · Migration of stand-alone application to Web application based Spring MVC framework
- JEE application conception and IC platform
- Code review, improve best practices and DB model and query optimization

J2EE, SPRING MVC, SPRING SECURITY, TILES JSP, HIBERNATE, APACHE TOMCAT MYSQL, MAVEN, JUNIT, JENKINS

#### Oct 2011 -Nov 2012

#### Java/C++ developer

SII - for CDN - Bouygues Telecom

- Write technical specifications
- Design and develop a CXF WS and backend

C/C++, JAVA, J2EE, WEBLOGIC, JUNIT, WS (CXF, SOAPUI), KSH, ECLIPSE, PL/SQL, SQL ORACLE, GEXCALIBER, QUALITE CENTER, CRUISECONTROL, CONTINUUS, SVN, WSDL, XSD

#### May 2011 -Oct 2012

#### Java developer

E-Map, Polytech'Nantes

- · Develop semantic search engine with data stream of professional
- Big data analytics learning process, classification and recommendation

JEE, profile API, UML, SQL SERVER, SVN

#### Oct 2009 -Aug 2010

#### **University educator**

Faculty of Sciences - University of Nantes

Web engineering, databases, algorithmics, computer and Internet certificate

JAVASCRIPT, HTML, CSS, WEB, PHP, SQL, ORACLE

### Research

#### 2004 - 2009 R&D Computer Science

**ESIGETEL & University of Nantes** 

- Post-PhD: Everyday sounds recognition in an smartHome environment - Robot CompanionAble.
- PhD thesis: Indexing audio documents: the case of bigData and data stream.